<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>David Ceperley | QMC-HAMM</title><link>/author/david-ceperley/</link><atom:link href="/author/david-ceperley/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>David Ceperley</description><generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>/images/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url><title>David Ceperley</title><link>/author/david-ceperley/</link></image><item><title>Stability and distortion of fcc-LaH10 with path-integral molecular dynamics</title><link>/publication/ly-lah10/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/publication/ly-lah10/</guid><description>&lt;p>The synthesis of the high temperature superconductor LaH&lt;sub>10&lt;/sub> requires pressures in excess of 100 GPa, wherein it adopts a face-centered cubic structure. Upon decompression, this structure undergoes a distortion which still supports superconductivity, but with a much lower critical temperature. Previous calculations have shown that quantum and anharmonic effects are necessary to stabilize the cubic structure, but have not resolved the low pressure distortion. Using large scale path-integral molecular dynamics enabled by a machine learned potential, we show that a rhombohedral distortion appears at sufficiently low pressures, even with quantum and anharmonic effects. We also highlight the importance of quantum zero point motion in stabilizing the cubic structure.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Phonons of metallic hydrogen with quantum Monte Carlo</title><link>/publication/ly-phonons/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/publication/ly-phonons/</guid><description>&lt;p>We describe a simple scheme to perform phonon calculations with quantum Monte Carlo (QMC) methods and demonstrate it on metallic hydrogen. Because of the energy and length scales of metallic hydrogen and the statistical noise inherent to QMC methods, the conventional manner of calculating force constants is prohibitively expensive. We show that our alternate approach is nearly 100 times more efficient in resolving the force constants needed to calculate the phonon spectrum in the harmonic approximation. This requires only the calculation of atomic forces, as in the conventional approach, and otherwise little or no programmatic modification.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>