<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Harley Johnson | QMC-HAMM</title><link>/author/harley-johnson/</link><atom:link href="/author/harley-johnson/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Harley Johnson</description><generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>/images/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url><title>Harley Johnson</title><link>/author/harley-johnson/</link></image><item><title>An efficient computational framework for charge density estimation in twisted bilayer graphene</title><link>/publication/rakib-charge-density/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/publication/rakib-charge-density/</guid><description>&lt;p>Electronic properties such as band structure and Fermi velocity in low-angle twisted bilayer graphene (TBG) are intrinsically dependent on the atomic structure. Rigid rotation between individual graphene layers provides an approximate description of the bilayer symmetry. Upon relaxation, in-plane displacement of the atoms in low angle TBG causes a change in the symmetry through the enlargement of the AB stacking regions and the reduction in size of AA and SP stacking regions. However, the effect of this in-plane relaxation on the charge density remains unexplored, because the necessary electronic structure calculations of such large supercells of low twist angle TBG are computationally infeasible. Therefore, we develop a computationally efficient framework that enables the exploration of the charge density symmetry of the low twist angle TBG. This framework is based on the Fourier representation of the charge density which presents high intensity Bragg peaks. We find that with the decrease of twist angle, low intensity satellite peaks also become apparent. Our framework incorporates these satellite peaks which reveals transformation of symmetry in the charge density distribution from high to low twist angle TBG. One striking outcome is the demonstration of the electron localization in the AA region of low twist angle TBG. Our framework helps to explain the effect of the atomistic relaxation on the charge density distribution and thus, it provides information about exotic electronic properties of low twist angle TBG at a low computational expense.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Accurate tight-binding model for twisted bilayer graphene describes topological flat bands without geometric relaxation</title><link>/publication/pathak-tbmodel/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/publication/pathak-tbmodel/</guid><description>&lt;p>A major hurdle in understanding the phase diagram of twisted bilayer graphene is the roles of lattice relaxation and electronic structure on isolated band flattening near magic twist angles. In this work, the authors develop an accurate local environment tight-binding model fit to tight-binding parameters computed from ab initio density-functional theory calculations across many atomic configurations. With the accurate parametrization, it is found that the magic angle shifts to slightly lower angles than often quoted, from around 1.05∘ to around 0.99∘, and that isolated flat bands appear for rigidly rotated graphene layers, with enhancement of the flat bands when the layers are allowed to distort. Study of the orbital localization supports the emergence of fragile topology in the isolated flat bands without the need for lattice relaxation.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Topologically derived dislocation theory for twist and stretch moiré superlattices in bilayer graphene</title><link>/publication/annevelink-dislocation/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/publication/annevelink-dislocation/</guid><description>&lt;p>We develop a continuum dislocation description of twist and stretch moiré superlattices in two-dimensional material bilayers. The continuum formulation is based on the topological constraints introduced by the periodic dislocation network associated with the moiré structure. The approach is based on solving analytically for the structural distortion and displacement fields that satisfy the topological constraints and that minimize the total energy. The total energy is described by both the strain energy of each individual distorted layer and a Peierls-Nabarro-like interfacial contribution arising from stacking disregistry. The dislocation core emerges naturally within the formalism as a result of the competition between the two contributions. The approach presented here captures the structure and energetics of twist and stretch moiré superlattices of dislocations with arbitrary direction and character, without assuming an analytical solution a priori and while accounting naturally for dislocation-dislocation image interactions. In comparisons to atomistic simulations using classical potentials, the maximum structure deviation is 6%, while the maximum line energy deviation is 0.019 eV/Å. Several applications of our model are shown, including predicting the variation of structure with twist angle and describing dislocation line tension and junction energies.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>